American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Coleman] Sellers, July 13, 1890; 7x4-1/2; Kelvin, William Thomson, Baron, 1824-1907
    Ayrshire, England, A.L.S. 2p. Approves proposals of E. Mascart, T. Turretini and W.C. Unwin for membership in A.P.S.
  - Note to the American philosophical society, July 15, 1890; 8x5; Wilson, Daniel, Sir, 1816-1892
    Toronto, A.N. in 3d person 1p. Presentation note which probably accompanied a copy of the Royal Society Transactions, Sect. II.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, July 16, 1890; 10 3/4x8 1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    London, Typed L.S. 3p. Propses W.C. Unwin for membership in A.P.S., endorsed by J.M. Wilson.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, July 16, 1890; 10 3/4x8 1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    London, Typed L.S. 2p. Proposes E. Cascart for membership in A.P.S., endorsed by J.M. Wilson.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, July 16, 1890; 10 3/4 x 8 1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    London, Typed L.S. 2p. Proposes Theodore Turretini for membership in A.P.S., endorsed by J.M.Wilson and W. Thomson. For Thomson's endorsement, see W. Thomson to C. Sellers; July 13, 1890.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Phila., July 16, 1890; 10 3/4 x 8 1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    London, Typed L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Proposes Cascart, Turretini and Unwin for membership in A.P.S. Proposals endorsed by J.M. Wilson and W. Thomson. Refers to Niagara Falls project. For Thomson's letter, see W. Thomson to C. Sellers; July 13, 1890.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., July 18, 1890; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Geographische Gesellschaft in Bremen
    Bremen, A.D.S.: M. Lindemen, on postal card 1p. and add., end. About exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Frederic [sic] Fraley, July 28, 1890; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Wilson, Joseph M. (Joseph Miller), 1838-1902
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 2p., end. by F.F. Endorses C. Sellers' proposals of Cascart, Turretini and Unwin for A.P.S. membership. Refers to rebuilding of A.P.S. Hall.
  - Letter to Secretary of American Philosophical Society [Henry Phillips], Aug. 20, 1890; 10-1/2x8; Bergen, Fanny D. (Fanny Dickerson), b. 1846
    Cambridge, Mass., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about James Mooney's Medical Mythology in Ireland.
  - Letter to [Fanny D. Bergen], Aug. 20, 1890; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., end.: L.S. with initial H. 1p. Draft. About James Mooney'_s Medical Mythology in Ireland. Refers to rebuilding of A.P.S. Hall.
  - Letter to Miss Ella Morison, Sept. 4, 1890; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Not necessary to call a meeting at present.
  - Letter to Secretary of American Philosophical Society [Henry Phillips], Sept. 6, 1890; 9x6; A.C. McClurg & Co.
    Chicago, Typed L.S.: H.H. Cook 1p., end. refers to rebuilding of A.P.S. Hall. Asks about price of complete set of Transactions and Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., Oct. 1, 1890; 8-3/4x6; A.C. McClurg & Co.
    Chicago, Typed L.S.: H.H. Cook 1p., end. refers to rebuilding of A.P.S. Hall End. mutilated. Refers to order for publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Philipps [sic], Oct. 3, 1890; 9x5-3/4; Krauss, Friedrich S. (Friedrich Salomo), 1859-1938
    Vienna, A.L.S. 1p., end. In German. Mentions Index to Transactions. Is working on Slavic ethnology. Describes poor treatment of Jews in Austria.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., Oct. 9, 1890; 8-3/4x6; A.C. McClurg & Co.
    Chicago, Typed L.S.: H.H. Cook 1p., end. Refers to order for publications.
  - Letter to Miss [Ella] Morrison [sic], Oct. 14, 1890; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. At Fraley's request, not necessary to call meeting for Oct. 17.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Phila., Oct. 14, 1890; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, William, 1824-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Refers to Coleman Sellers.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Oct. 29, 1890; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Evans, John, Sir, 1823-1908
    Nash Mills [Eng.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about Proceedings, No. 124. which he has not received.
  - Carler Legacy, Oct. - Nov., 1890; Unidentified
    6p.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Nov. 7, 1890; 10x8; Boardman, George Dana, 1828-1903
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Resignation from A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Nov. 9, 1890; 3x5; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    Germantown, [Pa.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Nov. 12, 1890; 8x5 1/4; Roberts, George B.
    Phila., Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Resignation from A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips?], Nov. 13, 1890; 6 3/4 x 4 1/2; Nünesdorff, Louise de
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. In French. Health will not allow her to work in A.P.S. Library, as proposed by J.C.Morris.
  - Letter to American Philosophical Society, Nov. 15, 1890; 5x8; Bell, I. Lowthian (Isaac Lowthian), 1816-1904
    Northallerton, England, A.L.S. 1p. Has received Proceedings, vol. 28. Requests list of papers he has sent to A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 17, 1890; 6x5; Whitney, Emma St. Clair
    Pottsville, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Requests information on Michael Hillegas
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 20, 1890; 10x8; Reiter, George
    Cincinnati, O., A.L.S. 4p., end. Describes his discovery in hydraulics. Asks for opinion of A.P.S.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 22, 1890; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Fidelity Insurance, Trust and Safe Deposit Company
    Phila., A.L.S.: R[obert] Patterson, V.P. Enc. wanting. 1p. Sends bill for storage of A.P.S. Library during rebuilding of Hall.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 24, 1890; 9 1/4x5 3/4; Fidelity Insurance, Trust and Safe Deposit Company
    Phila., A.L.S.: R[obert] Patterson 1p. Recalls bill for storage of A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 1, 1890; 11x8-1/2; Earle, Charles Warrington, 1845-1893
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on Palaeosyops and Allied Genera. Refers to E.D. Cope and H.F. Osborn. For printed paper, see Pamphlet Collection, vol. 408.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 5, 1890; 11x8 1/2; Earle, Charles Warrington, 1845-1893
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Sends return postage for his MS. on Paleosyops.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Dec. 5, 1890; 10-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., L.S. 1p., end.: Referred to Curators Asks A.P.S. to consider withdrawing Peale Stone Age collection from deposit at Academy of Natural Sciences, as Hall is now fireproof.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 6, 1890; 3X5; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
    [Phila.], A.N. In 3d person on postal card 1p. and add., end. by E[lla] M[orison] Change of address.
  - Letter to Frederic [sic] Fraley, Dec. 8, 1890; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Wilson, Joseph M. (Joseph Miller), 1838-1902
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Gives qualification of W.C. Unwin, E. Cascart and T. Turretini for A.P.S. membership.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips;], Dec. 9, 1890; 3x5; Earle, Charles Warrington, 1845-1893
    Princeton, N.J. A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Has received his paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 10, 1890; 3-3/4x5 1/2; Wertsch,
    Spremberg, [Germany], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns Volapük.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Dec. 15, 1890; 13x8; Carson, E. Frank
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns proposed monument to David Rittenhouse. Asks A.P.S. to join in petition for same.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 17, 1890; 10x8; Reiter, George
    Cincinnati, O., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his discovery in hydraulics.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Dec. 17, 1890; 10-1/2x8; Welsh, Herbert, 1851-1941
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Resignation from A.P.S.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 20, 1890; 9-1/2x6; Baker, John Remigius, 1818-1892
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Cannot serve on any committees.
  - Letter to Henry M. Phillips, Jr. [sic], Dec. 23, 1890; 8x5; Rosengarten, Frank H.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns sum appropriated for reception of American Chemical Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 24, 1890; 8x5; McCauley, Edward Yorke, 1827-1894
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges a committee appointment.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Dec. 26, 1890; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Lists committee. Etting Bequest: A. Biddle, W.S.W. Ruschenberger, R. Wood, J.S. Price, J.C. Fraley, Proceedings: E.D. Cope, G.F. Barker, E.Y. McCauley, H.F. Jayne, W.P. Tatham.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 27, 1890; 9-1/2x6; Fraley, Joseph Cresson, ca. 1848-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. On behalf of F.Fraley, his father, about nomination of P. Frazer as Curator.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 29, 1890; 9x6; Rosengarten, Frank H.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns sum appropriated for reception of American chemical society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 29, 1890; 11x8-1/4; New York (N.Y.). Committee on Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of Washington, 1789
    New York, Typed L.S.: Clarence W. Bowen, Secretary. 1p., end. Requests permission to photograph the Sully portrait of Jefferson.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., Dec. 30, 1890; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Returns form.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 31, 1890; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Arranges for a photograph of the Jefferson portrait.
  - Biographical sketch of Christian Frederick Dencke., [1890]; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Maisch, John M. (John Michael), 1831-1893
    A.MS. 2p. Printed in A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 28, p. 94. For covering letter, see F.A. Muhlenberg to H. Phillips, March 10, 1890.
  - Note to unidentifed recipient, [1890]; 4-1/2x4-1/4; Morison, Ella M.
    A.N. 1p. Gives price of issues of Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 4, 1891; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. and end. Accepts post as a Curator.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 5, 1891; 8x4-3/4; Wurts, Charles Stewart, 1830-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and end. Acknowledges election as A.P.S. Councillor.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 7, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Appoints committee to examine J. Lindahl's paper: J. Leidy, J.P. Lesley, A. Heilprin.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 9, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for J.H.J. Lindahl's paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 13, 1891; 8x5; Hill, A. J. (Alfred James), 1833-1895
    St. Paul, Minn., A.L.S. 2p. About Lewis and Clark journals.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], Jan. 20, 1891; 7x4-1/2; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper, "Geometry and Mechanics Deny Evolution."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 20, 1891; 10-1/2x7, 2-3/4x7-1/2; Wolff, P. E.
    Melbourne, Reproduction of A.L.S., with MS. corrections and additions. 2p. Enc. in MS. Concerns his forthcoming expedition to the Solomon Islands.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 21, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Committees will continue with same members as last Year.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 26, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Sorry to hear of his illness.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 29, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will postpone meeting until Phillips' health improves.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 29, 1891; 8x5-1/4; H[ouston], E[dwin] J[ames], 1847-1914.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns meeting of Library Committee.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Jan. 31, 1891; 8x5; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Change of address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 6, 1891; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Jannet, Claudio, 1844-1894
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p., end., and end. Concerns Carlier bequest to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 8, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Arranges meeting of Library Committee.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 10, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Appoints J.B. McMaster to prepare obituary of George Bancroft.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 10, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 16, 1891; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Sends Isidore Schwab to interview for job in library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 17, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Carlier legacy. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 17, 1891; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Recommends man to take care of A.P.S. books.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 18, 1891; 8x5; Etting, J. Marx
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Acknowledges A.P.S. decision in regard to will of F.M. Etting.
  - Letter to E[dwin] J[ames] Houston, Feb. 23, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns installing the library in its new quarters.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 24, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Arranges a meeting.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 26, 1891; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Gives opinion of workman sent by Phillips.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 27, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Arrange books if Library room is ready.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 2, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Magyar Földrajzi Társaság
    Budapest, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Antoine de Bereez 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 5, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns library business.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S. Providence [R.I.], March 6, 1891; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends paper on brain of limulus.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], March 8, 1891; 3x5; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, [R.I.], A.L.S. on postal card. 1p. and add Concerns his paper on limulus.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 10, 1891; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, [R.I.], A.L.S. 1p. Apologizes for sending in his paper on limulus.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 14, 1891; 11x8-1/2; North American Association for Propagation of Volapük
    Boston, A.L.S.: Alfred A. Post. 1p., end. Inquires about a tract by A.J. Ellis on universal language.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 18, 1891; March 16, 1892; 8x5, 3x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2 items of separate date pasted together 1p. Concerns members in arrears.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 26, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Recommends bearer, R. MacBride, as laborer.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 1, 1891; 8x5; Reed, Henry, 1846-1896
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Name of linguist is Emanuele Fronani (?)
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., April 2, 1891; 5x7-3/4; Abbot, Henry L.
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Incomplete. Asks that spelling of his name be corrected in the records.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], April 10, 1891; 6x4; Sarda, Har Bilas, Diwan Bahadur, 1867-1955
    Ajmer, India, A.L.S. 3p., end. Asks for copy of A.P.S. rules.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., April 13, 1891; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Sheafer, William L.
    Pottsville, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends notice of death of P.W. Sheafer.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 16, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], April 20, 1891; 9-1/2x6; McIlvaine, Charles
    Haddonfield N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end 9-1/2x6. Inquires a second time about copy of Gabb's paper on San Domingo.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 20, 1891; 9-1/2x6; McIlvaine, Charles
    Haddonfield, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Thanks for reply.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 24, 1891; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Asks to read paper on "A Fragment of Objectionable University-Extension Teaching." For printed paper, see: APS Proceeding vol. 29, pp.50-59.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 27, 1891; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Concerns his paper, "A Fragment of Objectionable University-Extension Teaching." For printed paper, see: A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 29, pp.50-59.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], May 1, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Naturwissenschaftliche Verein für Schleswig-Holstein
    Kiel, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Asks for exchanges.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 6, 1891; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 3p. Cannot attend meeting of officers of the Society.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 6, 1891; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Bureau central météorologique de France
    Paris, L.S.: G. Mascou (?) 1p., end. In French. Thanks for Nos. 131-134 of Proceedings. Asks for preceding numbers.
  - Letter to the Committee on Extended Accommodation, May 10, 1891; 9x5-3/4; American Philosophical Society. Building Committee. Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for its report. Reply written on verson. See J.C. Morris to H. Phillips, [May 11, 1891].
  - Letter to the [APS] Committee on Extended Accommodation, May 10, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for its report. Reply written on verso. See J.C. Morris to H. Phillips, [May 11, 1891].
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 11, 1891; 5-3/4x9; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Committee on extended Accommodation has not yet met. Written on verso of H. Phillips to Committee on Extended Accomodation, May 10, 1891.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 16, 1891; 10x7-3/4; Thorpe, Francis Newton, 1857-1926
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Enc. Asks to use J.B. McMaster's paper on Franklin for the Centennial Memorial Volume of the Univ. of Penna. Encloses advertising circular for Volume.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 19, 1891; 11x8-1/2; Lindahl, Josua, 1844-1912
    Springfield Ill., L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his paper on Megalonyx leidii. Refers to Prof. Leche (i.e., J.P. Lesley).
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 20, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Cannot attend meeting of Library Committee.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], May 25, 1891; 8x5; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns elections at last meeting. Refers to D.G. Brinton, S. Wood, Mr. Thober.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 2, 1891; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Instituto y Observatorio de Marina (Spain)
    San Fernando, Printed L. filled in in MS., and S.: J. Viniegro, Capitain de vaisseau. 1p. and end. Announces his appointment as director.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 4, 1891; 8x5-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks him to arrange meeting of J.C. Morris with the Library Committee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 10, 1891; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Cannot attend Library Committee meeting Authorizes Phillips or Morris to vote for him. Refers to E.J. Houston.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 19, 1891; 10-1/2x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., T.L.S. 6p. Résumé of the career of George Forbes, nominated for membership in the Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Phila., June 29, 1891; 8x5; Sarda, Har Bilas, Diwan Bahadur, 1867-1955
    Ajmer, India, A.L.S. 3p. Asks to be nominated for membership.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 2, 1891; 5-1/4x8; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. and end. Resignation from A.P.S.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, July 27, 1891; 10x8; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns size of exhibit cases for Peale Stone Age collection.
  - Letter to W[illia]m P. Tatham, Phila., July 29, 1891; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Makes arrangements to meet him.
  - Letter to W[illia]m P. Tatham, Phila., Aug. 1, 1891; 10x8; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], Typed L.S. with MS. additions 4p. Concerns his progress in redecorating A.P.S. Hall. Refers to various busts, portraits. Refers to the Rittenhouse telescope, J.C. Morris.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Aug. 2, 1891; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Cora, Guido, 1851-1917
    Turin, A.L.S. 2p., end., and end. Accepts election to A.P.S. Inquires after diploma. Arranges for sending of Proceedings.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Aug. 10, 1891; 11x8-1/2; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns use of bookcases in meeting room of A.P.S.Hall.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 8, 1891; 5-1/4x8; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end., and end. Asks to withdraw his resignation from A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Sept. 17, 1891; 8x5; Rogers, Robert William, 1864-1930
    Carlisle, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends his photograph for A.P.S. album.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of A.P.S., Sept. 19, 1891; 10x7-3/4; Missouri. Geological Survey
    Jefferson City, Mo., Typed L.S.: Arthur Winslow, State Geologist. 1p., end. Asks for copy of J.J. Stevenson, "Alleged Parallelism of the Coal Beds."
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Sept. 25, 1891; 8x5; Mott, Henry
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p., end. Enc., end. Sends receipt for McGill College's copy of the Proceedings, No. 135. Inquires about Nos. 124, 134.
  - Letter to E[lla M.] Morrison [sic], Sept. 26, 1891; 6-1/2x5-3/4; Van Gunden & Young
    Phila., L. 1p., and end. Signature wanting. Concerns cleaning of marble busts.
  - Receipt to the A.P.S. for four marble busts to be cleaned, Sept. 28, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Van Gunden & Young
    Phila., D.S.: Robert Charlton. 1p., end.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Oct. 12, 1891; 8-1/2x5-1/2; New York Academy of Sciences
    New York, A.L.S.: N.L. Britton, Librarian. 1p., end. Concerns Transactions. Refers to R.P. Whitfield.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Oct. 15, 1891; 8x5; Baker, William Spohn, 1824-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Endorses P.L. Ford's request to examine Jefferson draft of Declaration.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Oct. 15, 1891; 8x5; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p., end. Asks a third time to see Jefferson's draft of the Declaration of Independence. Is preparing a new edition of Jefferson's writings.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic; Phila.], Oct. 15, 1891; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    L.S. 2p. Encs. wanting. Concerns P.L. Ford's request to examine the Jefferson draft of the Declaration of Independence. Refers to W.S. Baker
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], Oct. 15. 1891; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., Oct. 21, 1891; 5-3/4x8; Hartford Theological Seminary
    Hartford, Conn., Mimeo. L.S.: A.T. Perry, Librarian. 1p., end. Concerns exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 21, 1891; 7x4-1/2; Jastrow, Joseph, 1863-1944